many Hunters maybe even including you
don't hunt for denial of service
vulnerabilities because they think you
cannot get good bounties for them but I
went on the internet and I extracted
138 paid back Bounty reports so this
assumption just isn't true there are
many interesting and complex denial of
service BS for which you can get great
Bounties in this video I will show you
some types of denial of service back as
usual uh with a few tips from my side
enjoy so out of those 138 reports over
half were regular types of Dos which I
called serers side dos which means that
you send something to the server and it
stops responding but usually it wasn't
just a simple you know send a lot of
requests and the server is down type of
buxs there are a lot of interesting ones
and one of my favorite bags that I
encountered is this one by Teddy cats in
GitHub where you had the the GitHub
actions functionality and often you
indicate the version that you want to
use with a shortcat like this if you
don't know what short shortash is every
comet is identified by a regular 40
hexadecimal character string like this
which let's be honest it's impossible to
to find a Collision in this however in
many places like here in this example we
are not using the full 40 character
hashes but we are using short hash of
only seven
characters and Teddy was simply curious
what will happen if he finds a collision
and he did find the collision and turned
out that he he thought that GitHub will
either choose one of these versions or
do something else but it started
throwing a 404 error uh which caused
GitHub actions to build which actually
caused GitHub actions to be unavailable
for everyone so it was a type of Dos
which simply broke one functionality for
everyone so it was it was quite a nice
bu he got I think
$5,000 for for this and a lot of denial
of service bags that I encountered were
bags like this where you just send one
good request and there is you know some
broken logic or some invalid assumption
which makes the server vulnerable but
there were also more let's say brute
forcey type of of doses but they they
weren't the simplest one that you just
send a lot of
request um for example here we have a
case in gitlab and specifically in their
markdown parsing
functionality where you would send this
sequence a lot of times this sequence in
markdown its opening of an image and the
hunter would send description full of
these
characters and precisely he used as many
of them as would fit into the
description of of gitlab uh length
limit and if he he would send this the
server would just time out after 1
minute uh so it's let's say more regular
type of Dos it's something I would think
about before when I would think about do
bugs where you sort of overload the
server uh with this probably there were
there was
some recursive looking for these
patterns or or something like this which
which caused the CPU to work really hard
and there was a good Bounty he was
rewarded
7.5
,000 and another um another Again One
Click denial of service here this is
actually my first paid back Bounty
report also submitted to to gitlab and
the thing here was in the all
functionality you had different clients
in the database which you could use and
to be secure when you would use any
client ID along with a redirect URI it
would take the redirect U that saved in
the database and it would compare it if
the redirect URI that you sent was the
same but there was one client called Web
internal which wasn't used this way it
was never used like I'm using it here
but it still had the record in the
database but this record didn't have the
redirect URI and when I sent a request
like this the app would the client would
exist so we wouldn't get into to an
error that would handle completely
invalid client and that it it tried to
extract registered registered redirect
URI which would later cause trying to
access a property of an undefined
object which would just shut down the
whole server and they paid $1,000 for it
which which was great at that time I was
just a student working part-time so
$1,000 then
I think was not much less than my
monthly salary uh working as a part-time
so I was really happy although now I
look at this um at these reports and I
see you know they paid 2.3k here 3K here
7K here for also one click doses so so
now I wonder why they decided to only
reward that one $1,000
but but whatever the next group that
that I have is called client side dos
and the difference here is that the
server responds normally the server is
not broken let's say in this category
but the whole um bu is happening on the
client side for example here we have the
the case in PayPal where you would just
use an invalid country as a local
parameter and it would start start to
redirect you save that that country in
the cookie and it would start to
redirect you to this URL with the
country in the URL even if the country
you would use was invalid it would still
keep doing this
so if you trick the victim into visiting
a URL like this with this parameter the
victim would just keep being redirected
to to this not existing page so they
would just get a for or not found we
know that both you and me we would know
how to solve this problem if if it would
happen to us because it's just in the
client side JavaScript but normal users
they don't they just want to use the
website and for them it doesn't really
matter if the website doesn't work
because of something that happens on the
client side or something that happens on
the server site for them the website
doesn't work period so so it's also um
funback here we have
3.2k Bounty um and another this is a a
really interesting back this this is
actually not in the JavaScript it's in
the mobile Instagram app and the thing
that happened here is turns out that
Instagram allowed accounts without a
username for some testing purposes for
developers and I I don't even know
what's the advantage of using account
with without the username instead of
generating something random as a
username but turned out they they use it
for some reason there there's probably a
very logical explanation of why they
needed this but when this username would
be shown to a normal user on Instagram
the app the mobile app would just crash
uh dossing the dossing the the
application for them dossing Instagram
for for the victim and how do you get
the victim to
be shown your profile without the
username you can for example join the
same group as them you can I think send
them a a message request or something
like this uh and their application would
just crash and they couldn't use
Instagram so this is also a type of of a
client site dos
buug the next group with 18 reports is
are software bugs uh and you know when I
do these case studies I focus on on web
related um vulnerabilities so we will
not dive deep
into use after free vulnerability or
something but just take a look at how
many of these reports are in Shopify
scripts back Bounty program it was a
separate program from Shopify itself
turned out that they had some scripts
some SDK or some scripts to to work with
the Shopify store and there were a lot
of bus in those scripts and those bus
were paid really really well we see 20
20 10K 8K 8K 8K 8K for those bugs and
then the next highest bount is 2.4k from
internet back Bounty so quite an
interesting interesting one but uh we'll
skip to the next category which is much
more relevant for us web hackers because
it's cash poisoning denial of service we
had 12 reports like this
uh five of which came from the original
article by James Kettle who discovered
the the technique or at least brought it
to to to mainstream let's say and to
remind you how this technique
works is um something like
this where when you have cash the goal
of cash is to serve the same response
for equivalent request
and what does equivalent requests mean
you know no two requests are the same if
they are sent from different users they
will always be a little bit different
you know at least the cookie will be
different so every cash server creat
something that's called Cash key so for
example it it saves there the host maybe
the
path parameters that are used basically
it should save in the cash key
everything that influences the response
and then whenever another request comes
it creates the cach key Compares if it's
the same and if it's the same it serves
the cached
response now when you find an input that
does influence the response but is not
in the cash key that's where you can get
a cash poisoning back and in this case
you can get a cash poisoning dos uh for
example we have hacker one as an example
here and the X forwarded Port would be
used when redirecting the the user we
can see that Port one to3 which of
course is an invalid one would be used
in the redirect location but it would
not be in the cach key which means that
any other person that would visit this
this endpoint would get serve an
invalid uh redirect to the one to fre
Port which would of course does the
functionality for them as I think this
is a a great bug because it's a Dos
which definitely has a great impact and
also we can test it reliably without
poisoning without risking that we will
break the application for all users take
a look here James uses do not poison
everyone parameter which of course is
not used by the application it's there
so that a user which is a regular user
visits this
endpoint this this parameter will make
their cash key different so the real
user that visits this website will not
be served this let's say malicious
response but if James would actually
intend
to break the website for everyone he
would remove this this parameter and
break the website for everyone but this
this small thing this is called a cash
Buster
parameter allows us to reliably test for
those cash poisoning bucks without you
know risking that we'll break the
website for anyone we'll make the
program angry and will not get the
Bounty so always always remember about
this I think this one was rewarded to 2
and a2k there was also 7 and 1 12K from
another company 10K from another company
so quite a good good bounties he got
from them and uh there was also a blog
post of finding cash poisoning get scale
there were also quite a few reports
there and always when I do these case
studies someone asks me in the comment
section if they can access this notion
database with all the reports the answer
is yes you can I always share these
databases in the bbr premium archive
because the case studies is actually the
part of bbr premium and I only share
usually about onethird of the case study
publicly so so this is the onethird of
the case study and the full version is
in bbr premium and if you were thinking
about joining in about two weeks there
is Black Friday and it will be the only
time in 2023 that there is any promotion
for bbr premium it will be as usual $20
off and probably before the next Black
Friday there will be a price rise so
this Black Friday will be the last time
that you can get access to BB premium
for year for
$80 and also even if the price Rises and
you subscribe before you keep the lower
price forever so it's the good time to
join during the Black Friday promo
coming back to to our
reports the next category um that that I
have was XML
RPC there were fre reports like this and
to be honest it's a bug that
even though here we we see that there
were bounties awarded for this I don't
really recommend you report this so the
bug is that you can make WordPress send
a ping to another
website and it sounds like ssrf but what
you are what Hunters were reporting here
is not actually an ssrf it's just the
ability to send a request to another
website which I think doesn't have
doesn't carry a lot of risk the the
rationality for reporting this is that
you can create a bot net and you can
create a distributed denial of service
attacks and I'm not saying this is not
true but if you if you're reporting a
bug like this I think you will get many
more Naas or informationals then you
will get actual bugs so I don't think
you should be reporting just this just
this functionality
uh if you could however find a zero day
in WordPress and make it an actual ssrf
uh you would be you would be a rich
person
definitely and the last group that I
have here which maybe it only has one
report that I found that was disclosed
but there is also a blog post which
which talks about it which men mentions
a lot of reports but it doesn't name
those targets so I couldn't you know
extract and put those reports in the in
the table but but he speaks about I
think 62 reports but what's the back the
back is exposed Google Maps API key so
when you want to embed Google Maps on
your website you need Google Maps API
key to be embedded in the Javascript
file and if it's embedded in Javascript
file by definition it is accessible to
all users including
attackers
now the thing that can go wrong here is
that this Google API key it can be
scoped for different Services if you're
using Maps embed API you should only
limit usage of this API key to this one
functionality to this one scope but
sometimes developers forget about this
and also the same key can be used for
different services like big query like
cloud like comp engine like something
else and this is this is the back this
is sort of over scoped API key but it's
reported as a denial of service the
reason why it popped in this case study
is the that it can lead to exhausting
your funds on your on your Google Cloud
key or just using your your funds as and
sort of using the Google API from your
website
um and the stats here are quite
interesting we have in total 62 reports
I calculated this 40 were accepted which
gives us about 2/3 of those reports and
a total of about 11 and a 12,000 for
them or about $300 per per one report
seems like mostly sinak accept this uh
so keep this in mind when when working
to be honest personally I wouldn't spend
my time trying to report this bug and
trying to argue my way my way in reports
that that this is a severe bug but as
you see you can make money from it so so
I'm not denying that it is actually a
valid bug that's it for this case study
I think it's just smart to look for bugs
in back Bounty which other Hunters
Overlook to to maybe focus on them focus
on bugs that that other Hunter Miss and
I think those qualifies as a back class
that that other people Overlook so I
hope this video was useful to you
remember that in bbr premium archive you
can also access case studies of ssrf RC
xses account takeovers and more and more
will be coming in the future as well and
for now if you want to check out another
free video I suggest you this one about
account takeover case St
for now thank you for watching and
goodbye